<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>web development on Blogging by Heath™</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/categories/web-development/</link><description>Recent content in web development on Blogging by Heath™</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 23:47:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://heathhenley.dev/categories/web-development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Working on a Fisheries Data Platform</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/the-fish-app/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 23:47:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/the-fish-app/</guid><description>TL;DR: A side project I&amp;rsquo;m working on is a web interface for the photos collected by a smart scale. The scale and its attached camera is deployed in remote areas and as the fish are caught they are weighed on the scale and their picture is taken. There is a mobile app that coordinates all of the and when the user is back in an area with service / wifi, the photos are sent up to a bucket.</description></item><item><title>Two similar apps with dissimilar tech stacks</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/implementing-similar-apps-with-dissimilar-stacks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 06:12:27 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/implementing-similar-apps-with-dissimilar-stacks/</guid><description>TLDR - My general takeaways from working on two similar apps. One the OG server-returns-html way with FastAPI/HTMX and one with Next.js using the app router / RSC / SSR. These are my quick take aways from the point of view of working on them from the perspective of a &amp;ldquo;non-web-dev dev&amp;rdquo;.
Intro I am currently working on two somewhat similar web apps, one using FastAPI with HTMX and one using Next.</description></item><item><title>Highlight Text From Multiple User Selections in React</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/highlight-text-from-selection-react/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 18:06:57 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/highlight-text-from-selection-react/</guid><description>TL;DR - This is a simple React component that allows you to make multiple highlights in a text from user selections.
Why? Working on a side project I wanted a way for users (and me as the current only user) to save words that they don&amp;rsquo;t know from a text. I found this great example blog that demonstrated one way to do this in React, but it didn&amp;rsquo;t allow for multiple highlights.</description></item></channel></rss>