<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>random on Blogging by Heath™</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/tags/random/</link><description>Recent content in random on Blogging by Heath™</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 08:30:07 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://heathhenley.dev/tags/random/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Drawing Cards without Replacement</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/drawing-without-replacement/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 08:30:07 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/drawing-without-replacement/</guid><description>TL;DR - working out the number of draws it will take you get an Ace if you&amp;rsquo;re pulling cards randomly without replacing them. Just doing it as &amp;ldquo;an exercise to the reader&amp;rdquo; - sparked by some questions that came about in an Advent of Code discord server I&amp;rsquo;m in. I work out the expected number of draws to the first &amp;lsquo;success&amp;rsquo; (drawing an Ace from a deck of cards, for example) from first principles, in a not-necessarily-rigorous-but-good-enough way (mathematicians don&amp;rsquo;t @ me.</description></item><item><title>Podcasts I've been into lately</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/podcasts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 08:11:51 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/podcasts/</guid><description>Here are some podcasts I&amp;rsquo;ve been into lately and why I like them.
Note - I&amp;rsquo;m not affiliated with any of these podcasts, I&amp;rsquo;m just a listener.
Tech Backend Banter - Lane from boot.dev interviews a variety of other devs (mostly) and talks about their experiences and projects. I particularly like that it&amp;rsquo;s not only Golang focused. It&amp;rsquo;s mostly entertainment, but I&amp;rsquo;ve learned a few things from it. I really enjoyed the episodes with John Crickett about &amp;lsquo;mechanical sympathy&amp;rsquo; (and also his coding challenges) and the one with Thomas Ballinger about convex.</description></item><item><title>How to Download an Image from a Google Doc</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/download-an-image-from-a-gdoc/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 23:20:05 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/download-an-image-from-a-gdoc/</guid><description>TL;DR: Either &amp;ldquo;File &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Download&amp;rdquo; the Google Doc as a web page, or open developer tools and watch for the browser to request the image from Google&amp;rsquo;s file servers.
The deets Here are two simple ways to get an image out of a Google Doc, at least until Google (maybe inevitably?) adds a “right click-&amp;gt; save image as” feature.
The first way is pretty straightforward, download the Google Doc containing the image files you would like to extract as a web page (File → Download → Web page (.</description></item><item><title>'Chicken' Nugget Hierarchy</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/fake-chicken-nugget-hierarchy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 20:54:43 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/fake-chicken-nugget-hierarchy/</guid><description>This is my (the only?) ranking:
Spicy dino-nuggets Spicy nuggets Dino nuggets Nuggets Keep in mind I&amp;rsquo;ve been a &amp;ldquo;most of the time non-meat eater&amp;rdquo; for a few years now, so maybe I&amp;rsquo;ve got it wrong when talking about the real meat nuggets&amp;hellip;For my other veggie friends out there, I&amp;rsquo;m a fan of Nuggs (if you&amp;rsquo;re into the substitute thing). They&amp;rsquo;re the closest I&amp;rsquo;ve had to real, good old after school freezer nuggs (I&amp;rsquo;m an adult, I swear, just ask my hairline).</description></item></channel></rss>