<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>django on Blogging by Heath™</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/tags/django/</link><description>Recent content in django on Blogging by Heath™</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 17:58:22 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://heathhenley.dev/tags/django/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Notes: Django w/ PostGIS on GCP Cloud Run and Github Actions</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/django-postgis-cloud-run-gh-actions/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 17:58:22 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/django-postgis-cloud-run-gh-actions/</guid><description>TL;DR: this a short post about the configuration steps I took to get django running with the GDAL extension and postgreSQL/postGIS backend. These notes are what it took to get it deployed on GCP Cloud Run, and to use Github Actions to run automated tests on push or pull request. Pretty straight forward, but I had to iterate a few times to get it right so hopefully this helps someone else.</description></item><item><title>New England Shipwreck Map</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/simple-wreck-map/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 15:28:45 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/simple-wreck-map/</guid><description>TL;DR - Here&amp;rsquo;s a list of shipwrecks plotted on an interactive map, all over the Narragansett Bay and greater New England area.
Motivation At FarSounder I work on the development software of 3D Forward Looking Sonar products. Part of that development process of course includes collecting data from a lot of different situations and running it through some processing algorithms to evaluate performance and make improvements. To that end, we&amp;rsquo;re often out on the Narragansett Bay collecting data with the system, and always looking for areas in the bay with interesting features that we can use to test and benchmark our algorithms (pilings, super steep shoals, rock piles, piers, etc).</description></item></channel></rss>