<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>algorithms on Blogging by Heath™</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/tags/algorithms/</link><description>Recent content in algorithms on Blogging by Heath™</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 17:32:43 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://heathhenley.dev/tags/algorithms/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Memoization in the Wild</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/memoization-in-the-wild/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 17:32:43 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/memoization-in-the-wild/</guid><description>Overview Memoization or memoisation is a method used to optimize programs. Usually, at least in my experience, it’s one of the first topics introduced when dynamic programming algorithms are being discussed. With a quick google search you can find the Wiki or a trillion other blogs about it - most will show the canonical example - the “hello world” of the topic - that is, using memoization to optimize a recursive implementation of a function that generates the n-th Fibonacci number (or sometimes a function computing factorials).</description></item><item><title>Triplet Counting Algorithmic Puzzle</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/triplet-counting-algorithm-puzzle/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 21:05:24 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/triplet-counting-algorithm-puzzle/</guid><description>We’ve all got a little more time on our hands lately due to social distancing and COVID-19 (unless you have young children). I’ve been partly entertaining myself by learning new programming languages and frameworks, and also with some programming puzzles on sites like HackerRank.
I found one problem I ran into recently particularly interesting, and I enjoyed figuring it out (read: drove me crazy for a bit). This post is a write up of the problem and the solution that I ended up with.</description></item></channel></rss>