<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blogging by Heath™</title><link>https://heathhenley.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Blogging by Heath™</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 17:32:43 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://heathhenley.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Memoization in the Wild</title><link>https://heathhenley.github.io/posts/memoization-in-the-wild/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 17:32:43 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.github.io/posts/memoization-in-the-wild/</guid><description>Overview Memoization or memoisation is a method used to optimize programs. Usually, at least in my experience, it’s one of the first topics introduced when dynamic programming algorithms are being discussed. With a quick google search you can find the Wiki or a trillion other blogs about it - most will show the canonical example - the “hello world” of the topic - that is, using memoization to optimize a recursive implementation of a function that generates the n-th Fibonacci number (or sometimes a function computing factorials).</description></item><item><title>'Chicken' Nugget Hierarchy</title><link>https://heathhenley.github.io/posts/fake-chicken-nugget-hierarchy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 20:54:43 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.github.io/posts/fake-chicken-nugget-hierarchy/</guid><description>This is my (the only?) ranking:
Spicy dino-nuggets Spicy nuggets Dino nuggets Nuggets Keep in mind I&amp;rsquo;ve been a &amp;ldquo;most of the time non-meat eater&amp;rdquo; for a few years now, so maybe I&amp;rsquo;ve got it wrong when talking about the real meat nuggets&amp;hellip;For my other veggie friends out there, I&amp;rsquo;m a fan of Nuggs (if you&amp;rsquo;re into the substitute thing). They&amp;rsquo;re the closest I&amp;rsquo;ve had to real, good old after school freezer nuggs (I&amp;rsquo;m an adult, I swear, just ask my hairline).</description></item><item><title>Computing Pi by Throwing Darts</title><link>https://heathhenley.github.io/posts/computing-pi-by-throwing-darts/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 21:17:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.github.io/posts/computing-pi-by-throwing-darts/</guid><description>In celebration of pi-day, let&amp;rsquo;s look at a method of computing pi using random numbers that is often presented in probability, statistics or other classes, as an elementary example of using random sampling and / or simulation.
In my case, the first time I remember seeing / hearing about this example was in a probability class, however we didn&amp;rsquo;t actually write any code to try it, we just looked at the idea.</description></item><item><title>Qué Hace Mi Empresa</title><link>https://heathhenley.github.io/posts/qu%C3%A9-hace-mi-empresa/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 18:40:07 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.github.io/posts/qu%C3%A9-hace-mi-empresa/</guid><description>Aviso: eso ha sido un trozo de texto que escribí para practicar mí español, no tiene nada que ver con FarSounder oficialmente.
Introducción En mi empresa, se llama FarSounder, hacemos un sistema de Sónar para los buques y los yates. El objetivo principal de este sistema es buscar cosas que sean peligrosas delante de la nave y bajo el agua. Hay un sensor que se pone en la proa, que está dirigido hacia delante, por supuesto.</description></item><item><title>Triplet Counting Algorithmic Puzzle</title><link>https://heathhenley.github.io/posts/triplet-counting-algorithm-puzzle/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 21:05:24 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.github.io/posts/triplet-counting-algorithm-puzzle/</guid><description>We’ve all got a little more time on our hands lately due to social distancing and COVID-19 (unless you have young children). I’ve been partly entertaining myself by learning new programming languages and frameworks, and also with some programming puzzles on sites like HackerRank.
I found one problem I ran into recently particularly interesting, and I enjoyed figuring it out (read: drove me crazy for a bit). This post is a write up of the problem and the solution that I ended up with.</description></item><item><title>Switching to the Python Pathlib Module</title><link>https://heathhenley.github.io/posts/python-pathlib-module/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 20:32:39 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.github.io/posts/python-pathlib-module/</guid><description>It’s been about a year or so since we officially upgraded all of our tooling at my job at FarSounder from Python 2.7 to Python 3 (3.6 at the moment). Aside from the syntactic changes, there have been a handful of updates in Python 3 that I’ve found to really increase the readability of our scripts. One of those updates (from back in Python 3.4) has been the introduction of the pathlib module.</description></item><item><title>About me</title><link>https://heathhenley.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.github.io/about/</guid><description>Hi, I’m Heath. I’m a Software Engineer at FarSounder, where I develop software for the processing and display of 3D Forward Looking sonar data. My path to Software Engineering has been non-traditional. I received a PhD in Chemical Engineering from the University of Rhode Island, during which I learned how to program and developed an interest and software development. I took a bunch of computer science classes and near the end of my grad career I also taught a few.</description></item><item><title>Publications and other writing</title><link>https://heathhenley.github.io/writing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.github.io/writing/</guid><description>Technical Blogs Argos Integration in Autonomous Systems Overcoming Real World Navigation Challenges Expedition Sourced Data Collection Program: Progress Update A First Look at Expedition Sourced Data Selected Conference Papers Deep Learning in Shallow Water - Link to paper available in the tech blog, or here. Applications of Today’s 3D Forward Looking Sonar for Real-time Navigation and Bathymetric Survey Performance of 3D Forward Looking Sonar for Bathymetric Survey Selected Journal Articles Fully compositional multi-scale reservoir simulation of various CO2 sequestration mechanisms Constant pressure Gibbs ensemble Monte Carlo simulations for the prediction of structure I gas hydrate occupancy Multiphase equilibrium flash with salt precipitation in systems with multiple salts Density and phase equilibrium for ice and structure I hydrates using the Gibbs–Helmholtz constrained equation of state Fully compositional and thermal reservoir simulation Full list available on Google Scholar.</description></item><item><title>Tutoring</title><link>https://heathhenley.github.io/tutoring/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.github.io/tutoring/</guid><description>Experience I have a ton of teaching experience in STEM topics, both in the classroom and in private tutoring setting. Subjects that I&amp;rsquo;ve tutored in, or taught as either a teaching assistant or an instructor include:
Algebra Calculus Differential Equations General Chemistry Chemical Engineering Thermodynamics (undergraduate and graduate level) Data Structures and Abstractions in C++ Introduction to Programming (for non-computer science majors) Request a meeting If you are looking for a tutor, let&amp;rsquo;s meet to discuss what your current goals are and see if we are a good fit.</description></item></channel></rss>