<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Books on Blogging by Heath™</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/books/</link><description>Recent content in Books on Blogging by Heath™</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://heathhenley.dev/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Abundance</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/books/2025/abundance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/books/2025/abundance/</guid><description>By Ezra Klein and Derek Thompson
Ezra Klein book about how dems/liberals f&amp;rsquo;d themselves and how they make things that they want to happen sometimes harder, often via regulation.
A lot of interesting ideas in there, not super prescriptive.
The idea of cities going from a place of opportunity to a luxury item hit me especially as we look to buy a place in the city.
NIMBY-ish and &amp;ldquo;lawn sign liberalism&amp;rdquo; also rang true as supporting some of my anecdotal experience in my neighborhood at least&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Art and Fear</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/books/2025/art-and-fear/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/books/2025/art-and-fear/</guid><description>By David Bayles and Ted Orland
DNF in February- skimmed the second half
I picked this up due to the awesome quote shared by the Vanta CEO in a podcast:
The function of the overwhelming majority of your artwork is simply to teach you how to make the small fraction of your artwork that soars.
There are some other good ones in there - but it could have ended at the first half or really been an essay.</description></item><item><title>Flowers for Algernon</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/books/2025/flowers-for-algernon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/books/2025/flowers-for-algernon/</guid><description>By Daniel Keyes
This was one that some people read in high school I think, I&amp;rsquo;ve heard get recommended a lot and wanted to check it out. I mostly enjoyed it, quick read, a lot of insight into mental decline.</description></item><item><title>Foundation</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/books/2025/foundation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/books/2025/foundation/</guid><description>By Isaac Asimov
Foundation, Foundation and Empire, Second Foundation
This is a second read through after last reading them in high school, still really liked them, I know it’s a trope but much better than the show and it’s not even similar to be honest - show is more like it’s “inspired by Foundation”.
Enjoyed them but got a bit burned out and didn’t feel like reading the last two.</description></item><item><title>If Cats Disappeared from the World</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/books/2025/if-cats-disappeared/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/books/2025/if-cats-disappeared/</guid><description>By Genki Kawamura
Finished: 9/26/25
I thought the idea of this was really interesting - main character is terminal, the devil appears and makes a deal to exchange a day of life for disappearing something from world each day. The catch is the devil picks each day&amp;hellip;
So yeah sounded interesting to me, and definitely did make me take a bit of time to reflect on the simple things in life&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>If on a winter's night a traveler</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/books/2025/if-on-a-winters-night/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/books/2025/if-on-a-winters-night/</guid><description>By Italo Calvino
Finished in January sometime (during vacation)
If on a winter’s night, a traveler - Italian Calvino
This was a second reading since reading it in college - I really love this book. Super meta about reading itself, confusing but in a good way, and of course great writing.
The reader (you, maybe) gets a book - and just as starts to pick up, notices there has been an error at the publisher and the next page is for for another book entirely&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Just Evil Enough</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/books/2025/just-evil-enough/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/books/2025/just-evil-enough/</guid><description>Finished:
By Alistair Croll
Subversive marketing tactics - with case studies and comparisons to traditional tactics.
Listening to this one on Audible - which is probably a mistake, I think I would be able to take more from it reading it. A bunch of case studies and comparisons to traditional marketing tactics - people who&amp;rsquo;ve &amp;ldquo;hacked&amp;rdquo; the system in a marketing sense.
His appearance on Lenny&amp;rsquo;s Podcast was what motivated me to get it, honestly could maybe just listen to that and get the idea instead, perhaps there&amp;rsquo;s more actionable stuff to gain from reading the book - here is the link.</description></item><item><title>Last Breath</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/books/2025/last-breath/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/books/2025/last-breath/</guid><description>By Peter Stark
This one was about humans in extreme conditions, and the physiology of what their body is going through in those situations. The stories were all invented except one I believe, but nonetheless I enjoyed the book - a bit morbid I guess…
Each chapter is a case study or story of a person meeting their demise in extreme conditions, with a lot of focus on the physiology of what’s happening to them.</description></item><item><title>Liar's Poker</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/books/2025/liars-poker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/books/2025/liars-poker/</guid><description>By Michael Lewis
This book is about the author’s career as a wall street trader. But mostly about the boys club of Wall Street trading, the rise and fall of Solomon Brothers, proudly ripping clients off, and people who strive for the unofficial title of “big swinging dick”
Kind for of the wolf of Wall Street of books - except it&amp;rsquo;s not satire - it&amp;rsquo;s an ode to the real finance bros of the day - people who really strive to contribute positively to society /s.</description></item><item><title>No Two Persons</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/books/2025/mythical-man-month/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/books/2025/mythical-man-month/</guid><description>By Frederick P. Brooks, Jr.
Finished: 12/17/25
A classic on software project management - definitely pretty out dated but some of the ideas are still relevant.
Don&amp;rsquo;t think I needed this one at this point, but glad I took the time to see what it had to offer.</description></item><item><title>No Two Persons</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/books/2025/no-two-persons/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/books/2025/no-two-persons/</guid><description>By Erica Bauermeister
Finished: 12/02/25
Based on the idea / quote by Edmund Wilson:
No two persons ever read the same book.
Each chapter follows a different person from very different walks of life as they are affected by a book in their own ways.
I love the idea of this one - I found that it kind of long in framing the lives of each individual person vs how they perceived or were affected by the story.</description></item><item><title>No Two Persons</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/books/2025/rejection/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/books/2025/rejection/</guid><description>By Tony Tulathimutte
Finished: 12/23/25
Another that with each chapter tells the story of a person&amp;rsquo;s life as they cross paths. I loved this book but it&amp;rsquo;s really clearly not going to be for everyone. A lot of internet culture and millennial themes, pretty dark, satirical and very precise writing. I literally laughed out loud a few times during this one. I think it&amp;rsquo;s intentional, but the only thing that took me a while to get used with the author&amp;rsquo;s writing style in this book is that there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of telling vs showing.</description></item><item><title>On Looking</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/books/2025/on-looking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/books/2025/on-looking/</guid><description>By Alexandra Horowitz
Finished: 9/13/25
About observing and not taking for granted our surroundings. I am really interested in this because in traveling, I have noticed that I tend to pay more attention to the areas I’m visiting - and I’ve been making more of an effort to do that at home.
The author walks around the same city block many times, first alone, then with her toddler, and then with other experts in very specific areas - asking them all what they see along the way.</description></item><item><title>Operating Systems: Three Easy Pieces</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/books/2025/ostep/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/books/2025/ostep/</guid><description>By Remzi H. Arpaci-Dusseau and Andrea C. Arpaci-Dusseau
This is the quintessential OS book that&amp;rsquo;s widely recommended and used for many OS courses. I realized I had never picked it up - and given that my path to SWE was a bit un-conventional, I still have a lot of gaps - this was a great way to fill them in, clear some things up and reinforce things I&amp;rsquo;ve forgotten long ago.</description></item><item><title>Project Hail Mary</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/books/2025/project-hail-mary/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/books/2025/project-hail-mary/</guid><description>By Andy Weir
Listened to this one with Maddy on a couple short road trips and around town. This was entertaining, a lot of STEM focus as the main character is a scientist - I don&amp;rsquo;t want to give too much about the plot away. He wakes up alone, knowing nothing about what&amp;rsquo;s going or where he is and has to piece it all together&amp;hellip;&amp;ldquo;coincidentally&amp;rdquo; he&amp;rsquo;s a scientist so that helps a bit.</description></item><item><title>Sea of Tranquility</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/books/2025/sea-of-tranquility/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/books/2025/sea-of-tranquility/</guid><description>By Emily St. John Mandel
Finished: 9/25/25
Interest time travel story - the main character visits different time periods to investigate an anomaly for the “Time Institute” - hoping to gain evidence about whether the universe is a simulation or not.
Short read and I enjoyed the writing style and the revelation of the plot.</description></item><item><title>Smoke and Mirrors</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/books/2025/humo-y-espejos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/books/2025/humo-y-espejos/</guid><description>By Neil Gaiman
This is a bunch of short stories that I was enjoying but I put down when I heard about the authors issues. Bummed because I really liked his books - American Gods and The Ocean at the End of the Lane in particular. Not sure why rich old guys can&amp;rsquo;t just leave young women alone.</description></item><item><title>Story of Your Life and Others</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/books/2026/story-of-your-life/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/books/2026/story-of-your-life/</guid><description>By Ted Chiang
Finished: 1/2/26
Summary This is a collection of short stories by Ted Chiang - they&amp;rsquo;re all sci-fi / fantasy themed and varied in theme and style. All of them are pretty short reads.
Notes This is one of my favorite books / collection and got me interested in short stories. I read this book a while back (idk like a decade now?) and some of the stories stuck with me even after all that time.</description></item><item><title>The Book Censor's Library</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/books/2025/book-censors-library/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/books/2025/book-censors-library/</guid><description>By Bothayna Al-Essa
Finished 9/1/25
This was entertaining, I read it in a couple days but mostly one sitting on a plane.
Inspired by Brave New World / 1984 / Fahrenheit 451. Shout outs and references to a lot of classic literature books. It&amp;rsquo;s about an authoritarian future where books are banned. The main character gets a job as a book censor where he must read with and evaluate books to ban without being affected by their meaning.</description></item><item><title>The Faithful Executioner</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/books/2025/faithful-executioner/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/books/2025/faithful-executioner/</guid><description>By Joel Harrington
Listened to this one
This is not my normal type of book - written based on the journal of a 16th century executioner. Learned a lot about that period, customs, social norms and especially odd and gruesome ways they killed people.</description></item><item><title>The First Fifteen Lives of Harry August</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/books/2025/harry-august/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/books/2025/harry-august/</guid><description>By Claire North
Finished: 11/23/25
In this universe, there are certain types of people who are reborn when they die - they&amp;rsquo;re given the chance to relive their life over again with knowledge of the previous live(s). Interesting concept, had a bit of a slow moving middle and then picked up. Overall I enjoyed it.</description></item><item><title>The Grace of Kings</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/books/2025/grace-of-kings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/books/2025/grace-of-kings/</guid><description>By Ken Liu
Finished: 10/17/25
I really enjoyed this first book in the fantasy series by Ken Liu. All of the other book of his that I have read have been short stories, so it was nice to see what he could do with a longer book - and the saga continues so he seems to be a man of extremes.
It&amp;rsquo;s a bit Game of Thrones-esque&amp;hellip; politics, warfare, meddling gods, etc.</description></item><item><title>The Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/books/2025/hitchhiker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/books/2025/hitchhiker/</guid><description>By Douglas Adams
Another second read - just nice feel good funny reads for me. I didn’t feel like rereading the whole 5 part trilogy, but the first two were enough.
Not much to say about these - I find them entertaining and packed with great one liners&amp;hellip;
They hung in the air in much the same way that bricks don&amp;rsquo;t.
Now there&amp;rsquo;s a frood who really knows where his towel is.</description></item><item><title>The Science of Storytelling</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/books/2025/science-of-story-telling/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/books/2025/science-of-story-telling/</guid><description>By Will Storr
Just getting started - taking a more psychology focused approach than trying to give rules, like other storytelling approaches do. One quote I liked in there already:
Most aesthetic absolutes turn relative under pressure.
Even though he’s talking about storytelling - relevant for much more.
There were some technical tips mentioned like show not tell, and the “South Park” story advice (no “and then”).
The most I got from it on the first listen - is that people create a mental model of reality, they are all distinct and sometimes flawed.</description></item><item><title>Wild Snail Eating</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/books/2025/wild-snail-eating/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/books/2025/wild-snail-eating/</guid><description>By Elisabeth Tova Bailey
Listened to this one - the author is bedridden, her friend brings her a flower that happens to have a garden snail on it. She befriends the snail and we readers get to learn more about snails (which I’ve mostly already forgotten) than I thought there was to know.
This was another book that like [[On Looking]] - encouraged me to make sure I am more present and paying attention to more of the small things around me, for that I appreciate it.</description></item><item><title>Zen and the Art of Motorcycle Maintenance</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/books/2025/motorcyle-maint/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/books/2025/motorcyle-maint/</guid><description>By Robert Pirsig
Not really my cup of coffee but I get the idea - “could have been an e-mail” kind of thing for me, or at least an essay. Maybe in it&amp;rsquo;s time it was better relative to the other books around. It’s one of those books that I’ve heard mentioned for years, so had to read it to see what was going on.
Basically
there’s always a balance between logic and emotion (“classical” and “romantic”) care and attention to detail, beauty in small things, quality very much the main thread engage deeply with work and life as “the way” “quality” is the key to everything</description></item></channel></rss>