<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>sales on Blogging by Heath™</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/categories/sales/</link><description>Recent content in sales on Blogging by Heath™</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 17:44:04 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://heathhenley.dev/categories/sales/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Opinion: 'Once They're Sold Stop Selling' promotes the wrong attitude</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/once-theyre-sold-stop-selling-is-bull/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 17:44:04 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/once-theyre-sold-stop-selling-is-bull/</guid><description>TL;DR: “Once they’re sold, stop selling”, in the way that it&amp;rsquo;s usually interpreted, is bad &amp;ldquo;classic sales advice&amp;rdquo; depending on the goals of your organization and how you view the role of a sales person. A big grain of salt: I&amp;rsquo;m not in sales, I&amp;rsquo;m an engineer, about 80% of my day to day is development and post sales support.
We’ve all heard it before… some form of “when you’ve got the sale, shut up” or, “once they’re sold, stop selling”.</description></item><item><title>Modeling Sales Pipeline using Monte Carlo Simulation</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/modeling-sales-pipeline-with-monte-carlo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 12:44:58 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/modeling-sales-pipeline-with-monte-carlo/</guid><description>TL;DR - Monte Carlo Simulation can be used to model your historical sales pipeline data to account for some of the randomness and uncertainty in the sales process. In this post, Monte Carlo Simulation is introduced and then applied to the same case introduced in a previous post.
What is Monte Carlo Simulation? Monte Carlo Simulation is used to simulate a process using random sampling. It is a very general technique that can be used to model all kinds of processes in fields ranging from physics and chemistry, to economics and finance.</description></item><item><title>Modeling a Sales Pipeline as a Markov Chain</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/modeling-a-sales-pipeline-as-a-markov-chain/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2023 17:27:59 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/modeling-a-sales-pipeline-as-a-markov-chain/</guid><description>TL;DR - Using a Markov Chain to model your historical sales pipeline data can help you understand the probability of eventually closing a deal based on (1) the stage the opportunity is currently in and (2) your historical data. This lets you estimate the future value of your current pipeline based on your own past data.
What is a Markov Chain? It is a mathematical model used to describe how probabilistic systems or processes evolve over time.</description></item></channel></rss>