<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>notes on Blogging by Heath™</title><link>https://heathhenley.github.io/tags/notes/</link><description>Recent content in notes on Blogging by Heath™</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 23:20:05 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://heathhenley.github.io/tags/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to Download an Image from a Google Doc</title><link>https://heathhenley.github.io/posts/download-an-image-from-a-gdoc/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 23:20:05 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.github.io/posts/download-an-image-from-a-gdoc/</guid><description>TL;DR: Either &amp;ldquo;File &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Download&amp;rdquo; the Google Doc as a web page, or open developer tools and watch for the browser to request the image from Google&amp;rsquo;s file servers.
The deets Here are two simple ways to get an image out of a Google Doc, at least until Google (maybe inevitably?) adds a “right click-&amp;gt; save image as” feature.
The first way is pretty straightforward, download the Google Doc containing the image files you would like to extract as a web page (File → Download → Web page (.</description></item><item><title>Key Learnings from NSF I-CORPS: 6 years later</title><link>https://heathhenley.github.io/posts/key-learnings-from-icorps/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 13:00:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.github.io/posts/key-learnings-from-icorps/</guid><description>TL;DR: Listen to customers, test your assumptions, follow the data, repeat
I participated in the NSF I-CORPS program quite a while ago now (LA Node, Fall 2016). The goal of the program is to assist scientists with technology transfer. It&amp;rsquo;s basically a crash course in entrepreneurship for STEM researchers. The program takes place over about 8 weeks and participants interview at least 100 people (customers, competitors, thought leaders, and partners) with the goal of finding product-market fit and determining the feasibility of commercializing the result of their NSF sponsored research project.</description></item></channel></rss>