<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Blogging by Heath™</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Blogging by Heath™</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 09:19:59 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://heathhenley.dev/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Modeling the Cooling in a Propane Tank</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/campstove-cheme/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 09:19:59 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/campstove-cheme/</guid><description>TL;DR: In a recent camping trip we noticed just how cold our propane tank was getting after cooking for a while - we started out pretty chilly anyway (about 50 F). The physics of this is cool and I wanted to play with modeling it.
I have one of these little two burner propane stoves that we use when camping, it looks something like this:
While we were cooking breakfast and boiling water for coffee, we noticed that the propane tank was getting super cold - there was not only a thick layer of frost forming on the outside, but a small chunk of solid ice on the bottom of the tank where it met the picnic table&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Podcasts I've been into lately</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/podcasts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 08:11:51 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/podcasts/</guid><description>Here are some podcasts I&amp;rsquo;ve been into lately and why I like them.
Note - I&amp;rsquo;m not affiliated with any of these podcasts, I&amp;rsquo;m just a listener.
Tech Backend Banter - Lane from boot.dev interviews a variety of other devs (mostly) and talks about their experiences and projects. I particularly like that it&amp;rsquo;s not only Golang focused. It&amp;rsquo;s mostly entertainment, but I&amp;rsquo;ve learned a few things from it. I really enjoyed the episodes with John Crickett about &amp;lsquo;mechanical sympathy&amp;rsquo; (and also his coding challenges) and the one with Thomas Ballinger about convex.</description></item><item><title>Two similar apps with dissimilar tech stacks</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/implementing-similar-apps-with-dissimilar-stacks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 06:12:27 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/implementing-similar-apps-with-dissimilar-stacks/</guid><description>TLDR - My general takeaways from working on two similar apps. One the OG server-returns-html way with FastAPI/HTMX and one with Next.js using the app router / RSC / SSR. These are my quick take aways from the point of view of working on them from the perspective of a &amp;ldquo;non-web-dev dev&amp;rdquo;.
Intro I am currently working on two somewhat similar web apps, one using FastAPI with HTMX and one using Next.</description></item><item><title>Notes: gradient descent, Newton-Raphson, Lagrange Multipliers</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/numerical-methods/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 00:15:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/numerical-methods/</guid><description>TL;DR: A quick &amp;ldquo;non-mathematical&amp;rdquo; introduction to the most basic forms of gradient descent and Newton-Raphson methods to solve optimization problems involving functions of more than one variable. We also look at the Lagrange Multiplier method to solve optimization problems subject to constraints (and what the resulting system of nonlinear equations looks like, eg what we could apply Newton-Raphson to, etc).
Introduction Optimization problems are everywhere in engineering and science. If you can model your problem in a way that can write down some function that should be minimized or maximized (the objective function) to get the solution you want, even in cases where there is no analytical solution (most real cases), you can often obtain a numerical solution.</description></item><item><title>Notes: 'Hacking' on S63</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/hacking-on-s63/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 17:15:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/hacking-on-s63/</guid><description>TL;DR: The S63 encryption scheme is old and can be broken pretty easily depending on the information you have. These are some notes on how with a simple Python script to show what I mean.
So this is an old standard that will soon be replaced by S100, but it&amp;rsquo;s still in place and used today. The encryption part of the scheme is mostly to allow data suppliers to license their data to users in a standardized way and collected payment for access to that data.</description></item><item><title>How Does S-63 Electronic Navigational Chart (ENC) Format Work?</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/how-does-s63-enc-format-work/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 19:18:13 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/how-does-s63-enc-format-work/</guid><description>TL;DR: S-63 is a standard used to encrypt official Electronic Navigational Charts (ENCs). Encryption and signing allow clients to be sure that they have official data and that it has not been tampered with. It also make it possible for data providers to license sections of the charts (cells) and be sure that they are not being shared illegally / pirated. This post gives an overview of the process and shows how to implement the key steps.</description></item><item><title>Newton Fractals Are Cool! And a Quick Intro to Newton's Method</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/newton-fractals-are-cool/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 12:46:44 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/newton-fractals-are-cool/</guid><description>Newton&amp;rsquo;s method is a root-finding algorithm that can be used to find the roots of differentiable functions. It is a very simple algorithm to implement, and it converges quickly in most cases, of course depending on the function. It is often used to find the roots of polynomials. For instance, in Chemical Engineering properties calculations, often cubic equations of state are used to model the behavior of fluids. These equations of state are cubic polynomials and most solved for their roots in most cases in order to compute fluid properties and phase equilibria.</description></item><item><title>Add Callout Captions to Camtasia 2023</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/add-callout-captions-to-camtasia-2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 19:14:18 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/add-callout-captions-to-camtasia-2023/</guid><description>TL;DR: Use the script below to add captions from a .srt file to a Camtasia 2023 project as callouts so they can be edited and styled.
The script is available on GitHub. The Camtasia project file is just a JSON file, so this parses the captions from the .srt file and adds them to the project file as callouts.
Not intended to produce polished captions, but rather to get the captions into the project so they can be edited and styled - basically as a time saver for the initial captioning process.</description></item><item><title>The Cryptopals Challenges</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/notes-from-cryptopals-challenges/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 12:58:01 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/notes-from-cryptopals-challenges/</guid><description>TL;DR: I&amp;rsquo;m working through the Cryptopals Cryptography Challenges, starting with knowing nothing about cryptography. These are my (not so) random notes and takeaways from them. They generally seem to follow a pattern of introducing a concept in cryptography (repeating key XOR, ECB mode, CBC mode, stream ciphers, etc) and then having you break it in some way(s). I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to turn my notes on some of these in to more detailed posts at some point, but for now, this mostly &amp;lsquo;stream of thought&amp;rsquo; that I&amp;rsquo;m updating as I work through them.</description></item><item><title>Random Notes About Python's Random Module</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/python-random-module-random-notes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 12:10:44 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/python-random-module-random-notes/</guid><description>TL;DR: Use the functions in the random module for modeling, simulations, games, sampling, etc. but use os.urandom, secrets, or random.SystemRandom for cryptographic applications. I know very little about cryptography and security, these are just my notes about stuff I recently learned.
It uses the Mersenne Twister algorithm, which is a pseudorandom number generator with a period of 2^19937-1. It is one of the most widely used PRNGs in the world, and suitable for many applications.</description></item><item><title>Error Checking out Large Repo on GitHub Actions Windows Runner</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/gh-actions-clone-windows-runner-error/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 18:07:36 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/gh-actions-clone-windows-runner-error/</guid><description>TL;DR: If you&amp;rsquo;re getting a weird looking Error: fatal: fetch-pack: invalid index-pack output error checking out a large repo on a GitHub Actions using a Windows Runner, try switching to use HTTPS instead of SSH for your clones (by providing a personal access token instead of an SSH key).
Summary I was recently working on getting CI setup for a project that has a pretty large repo with a few submodules and uses LFS for some large binaries.</description></item><item><title>Some tips for working at a small company (mostly for devs)</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/small-company/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 19:01:27 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/small-company/</guid><description>Some tips for Working at a Smaller Company (mostly for devs) TL;DR - A small company can be a great place to learn, and it can be a lot easier to see the effects of the results of your work. At the same time, you likely won’t have access to the same structure, level of mentorship, clarity of career path / progression, or resources. In my experience you need to be the kind of person who (1) is happy with being more of a generalist, and (2) take responsibility for your own learning - eg fill in gaps were necessary, go deeper when needed, and lean on outside resources, friends, etc.</description></item><item><title>Highlight Text From Multiple User Selections in React</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/highlight-text-from-selection-react/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 18:06:57 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/highlight-text-from-selection-react/</guid><description>TL;DR - This is a simple React component that allows you to make multiple highlights in a text from user selections.
Why? Working on a side project I wanted a way for users (and me as the current only user) to save words that they don&amp;rsquo;t know from a text. I found this great example blog that demonstrated one way to do this in React, but it didn&amp;rsquo;t allow for multiple highlights.</description></item><item><title>Writing in Target Language Everyday and Writescribir</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/writing-in-target-language-everyday/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 08:00:26 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/writing-in-target-language-everyday/</guid><description>TL;DR: I think that writing in your target language everyday is a great way to improve your writing skills! So much so that I&amp;rsquo;m working on an app to help with that. Check it out at writescribir.com.
I think that writing in your target language everyday is a great way to improve and to keep your new language on your mind, especially when you don&amp;rsquo;t live in a country where your target language is spoken (or primarily spoken).</description></item><item><title>Modeling Sales Pipeline using Monte Carlo Simulation</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/modeling-sales-pipeline-with-monte-carlo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 12:44:58 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/modeling-sales-pipeline-with-monte-carlo/</guid><description>TL;DR - Monte Carlo Simulation can be used to model your historical sales pipeline data to account for some of the randomness and uncertainty in the sales process. In this post, Monte Carlo Simulation is introduced and then applied to the same case introduced in a previous post.
What is Monte Carlo Simulation? Monte Carlo Simulation is used to simulate a process using random sampling. It is a very general technique that can be used to model all kinds of processes in fields ranging from physics and chemistry, to economics and finance.</description></item><item><title>Notes: Workaround to use Railway with Git Submodules</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/workaround-railway-with-git-submodules/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 20:04:45 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/workaround-railway-with-git-submodules/</guid><description>TL;DR - Railway doesn&amp;rsquo;t support git submodules yet. They probably will at some point - here&amp;rsquo;s the feature request. In the meantime, here&amp;rsquo;s a quick workaround to get it working / deploying.
Use Github Workflow You can deploy projects to railway.app directly from github, but they do not support git submodules yet. So your repo gets cloned as usual and railway attempts to build/deploy. However, the submodules are not included, and the build will fail.</description></item><item><title>Update Github Profile Readme Dynamically using a Github Workflow</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/update-gh-readme-with-action/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 20:44:26 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/update-gh-readme-with-action/</guid><description>TL;DR: Update your Github Profile Readme dynamically with recent blog posts. There&amp;rsquo;s an example (profile and code).
Github Profile Readme Github introduced the option to a add profile readme, which is a special repository that is used to display a readme on your profile page. I wanted to post links to my recent blog posts there, so I wrote a simple python script to check for the latest X posts, and update the readme with links to them.</description></item><item><title>Refactoring my Simple Python Chatbot Module</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/refactoring-chatbot-python-module/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 23:40:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/refactoring-chatbot-python-module/</guid><description>TL;DR: cleaned up a simple chatbot module that I wrote in Python, originally as a way to impersonate a friend in my Slack chat.
How it started I wrote a chatbot in python to impersonate one of my friends on Slack. It was a fun project, but originally I set it up a pretty hacky way. Here&amp;rsquo;s an example of what it looks like integrated into slack:
Ok so that&amp;rsquo;s a pretty goofy impersonation of a friend of mine (littered with inside jokes) - but it can actually be useful.</description></item><item><title>Notes: Django w/ PostGIS on GCP Cloud Run and Github Actions</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/django-postgis-cloud-run-gh-actions/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 17:58:22 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/django-postgis-cloud-run-gh-actions/</guid><description>TL;DR: this a short post about the configuration steps I took to get django running with the GDAL extension and postgreSQL/postGIS backend. These notes are what it took to get it deployed on GCP Cloud Run, and to use Github Actions to run automated tests on push or pull request. Pretty straight forward, but I had to iterate a few times to get it right so hopefully this helps someone else.</description></item><item><title>Where We Went: Mallorca</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/where-we-went-mallorca/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 17:36:01 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/where-we-went-mallorca/</guid><description>Where We Went: Mallorca These are places visited over two short trips, one in September of 2022 and one in April/May of 2023. If I go again, I&amp;rsquo;ll update this list!
TL;DR Mallorca is great! My favorite place is Sineu because it&amp;rsquo;s small and quiet but still has a couple restaurants, bars, a brewery, wineshop and beautiful old town. My favorite hike was the Deia loop and stopping at Cala Deia for beach time.</description></item><item><title>Modeling a Sales Pipeline as a Markov Chain</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/modeling-a-sales-pipeline-as-a-markov-chain/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2023 17:27:59 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/modeling-a-sales-pipeline-as-a-markov-chain/</guid><description>TL;DR - Using a Markov Chain to model your historical sales pipeline data can help you understand the probability of eventually closing a deal based on (1) the stage the opportunity is currently in and (2) your historical data. This lets you estimate the future value of your current pipeline based on your own past data.
What is a Markov Chain? It is a mathematical model used to describe how probabilistic systems or processes evolve over time.</description></item><item><title>ChE 513 Course Materials - ChE Thermodynamics (Graduate Level)</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/thermo-class-materials/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 13:08:44 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/thermo-class-materials/</guid><description>In the Fall of 2017, while finishing my PhD I taught ChE thermodynamics to a class of graduate and advanced undergraduate students at the University of Rhode Island. I recently discovered some of my old course materials and decided to post them publically. It was a project based class, so after the first few lectures, most of the class meetings were spent working on problems and projects.
Either way, I hope they are useful to someone!</description></item><item><title>How to Download an Image from a Google Doc</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/download-an-image-from-a-gdoc/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 23:20:05 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/download-an-image-from-a-gdoc/</guid><description>TL;DR: Either &amp;ldquo;File &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Download&amp;rdquo; the Google Doc as a web page, or open developer tools and watch for the browser to request the image from Google&amp;rsquo;s file servers.
The deets Here are two simple ways to get an image out of a Google Doc, at least until Google (maybe inevitably?) adds a “right click-&amp;gt; save image as” feature.
The first way is pretty straightforward, download the Google Doc containing the image files you would like to extract as a web page (File → Download → Web page (.</description></item><item><title>YOLO-ing All the Traffic Cams</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/yolo-all-the-traffic-cams/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 15:40:04 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/yolo-all-the-traffic-cams/</guid><description>TL;DR - Here&amp;rsquo;s a web app to list labelled traffic cam images from the RI DOT website. I used YOLO (You Only Look Once) to detect objects (vehicles) in the images and FastAPI to serve the results to a React app. The displays the cam images and results and uses LeafletJS to display the cameras on a map. The backend is hosted on Railway and the front end on Github Pages.</description></item><item><title>New England Shipwreck Map</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/simple-wreck-map/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 15:28:45 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/simple-wreck-map/</guid><description>TL;DR - Here&amp;rsquo;s a list of shipwrecks plotted on an interactive map, all over the Narragansett Bay and greater New England area.
Motivation At FarSounder I work on the development software of 3D Forward Looking Sonar products. Part of that development process of course includes collecting data from a lot of different situations and running it through some processing algorithms to evaluate performance and make improvements. To that end, we&amp;rsquo;re often out on the Narragansett Bay collecting data with the system, and always looking for areas in the bay with interesting features that we can use to test and benchmark our algorithms (pilings, super steep shoals, rock piles, piers, etc).</description></item><item><title>Key Learnings from NSF I-CORPS: 6 years later</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/key-learnings-from-icorps/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 13:00:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/key-learnings-from-icorps/</guid><description>TL;DR: Listen to customers, test your assumptions, follow the data, repeat
I participated in the NSF I-CORPS program quite a while ago now (LA Node, Fall 2016). The goal of the program is to assist scientists with technology transfer. It&amp;rsquo;s basically a crash course in entrepreneurship for STEM researchers. The program takes place over about 8 weeks and participants interview at least 100 people (customers, competitors, thought leaders, and partners) with the goal of finding product-market fit and determining the feasibility of commercializing the result of their NSF sponsored research project.</description></item><item><title>Smart Pointer Pointers</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/smart-pointer-pointers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 10:05:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/smart-pointer-pointers/</guid><description>TL;DR - Switch raw heap pointers to unique_ptrs when possible. If your heap allocated resource needs multiple owners, use a shared_ptr instead.
I find myself reviewing C++ smart pointer types over and over again. I guess for me, it’s just been one of those things that doesn’t stick, or perhaps I’ve only needed to use them infrequently enough to forget about them. So, here’s a note to myself, and anyone else dying to read about smart pointers in C++.</description></item><item><title>Resumen: El Valle De Los Lobos</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/resumen-el-valle-de-los-lobos/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 13:47:41 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/resumen-el-valle-de-los-lobos/</guid><description>Introducción El valle de los lobos es un libro para adolescentes que narra las aventuras inesperadas de una niña que se llama Dana. Es un libro interesante, aunque sea un poco juvenil. En mi opinión, es útil para los estudiantes del idioma porque la historia es fácil de entender y no se usa un vocabulario tan complejo, ya que el libro se escribió para los adultos jóvenes. De hecho, es muy parecido a los libros de Harry Potter.</description></item><item><title>Shut the Box</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/shut-the-box/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 21:11:13 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/shut-the-box/</guid><description>TL;DR - choose either the option containing the largest number, or the fewest tiles and you&amp;rsquo;ll be ok!
Read on to learn more&amp;hellip;
What am I talking about? Over the summer at a friends house, I was presented with an “old bar game” that I was completely unfamiliar with. It’s a wooden tray, with the numbers 1-12 printed in ascending order on little wooden tiles.
Here’s an example of what it looks like:</description></item><item><title>¿Cómo Aprender Un Idioma Nuevo?</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/como-aprender-un-idioma-nuevo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 17:23:07 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/como-aprender-un-idioma-nuevo/</guid><description>Si en tu vida no has aprendido un idioma después de tu primer idioma, puede ser difícil empezar. Estos son mis consejos sobre el tema. Si sigues algunos de mis consejos, mejorarás tus conocimientos de tu segundo idioma. Pero también es importante que tengas en cuenta el hecho de que no soy profesor ni experto en el tema. Es posible que lo que me sirve a mi no te sirva a ti.</description></item><item><title>Memoization in the Wild</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/memoization-in-the-wild/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 17:32:43 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/memoization-in-the-wild/</guid><description>Overview Memoization or memoisation is a method used to optimize programs. Usually, at least in my experience, it’s one of the first topics introduced when dynamic programming algorithms are being discussed. With a quick google search you can find the Wiki or a trillion other blogs about it - most will show the canonical example - the “hello world” of the topic - that is, using memoization to optimize a recursive implementation of a function that generates the n-th Fibonacci number (or sometimes a function computing factorials).</description></item><item><title>'Chicken' Nugget Hierarchy</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/fake-chicken-nugget-hierarchy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 20:54:43 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/fake-chicken-nugget-hierarchy/</guid><description>This is my (the only?) ranking:
Spicy dino-nuggets Spicy nuggets Dino nuggets Nuggets Keep in mind I&amp;rsquo;ve been a &amp;ldquo;most of the time non-meat eater&amp;rdquo; for a few years now, so maybe I&amp;rsquo;ve got it wrong when talking about the real meat nuggets&amp;hellip;For my other veggie friends out there, I&amp;rsquo;m a fan of Nuggs (if you&amp;rsquo;re into the substitute thing). They&amp;rsquo;re the closest I&amp;rsquo;ve had to real, good old after school freezer nuggs (I&amp;rsquo;m an adult, I swear, just ask my hairline).</description></item><item><title>Computing Pi by Throwing Darts</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/computing-pi-by-throwing-darts/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 21:17:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/computing-pi-by-throwing-darts/</guid><description>In celebration of pi-day, let&amp;rsquo;s look at a method of computing pi using random numbers that is often presented in probability, statistics or other classes, as an elementary example of using random sampling and / or simulation.
In my case, the first time I remember seeing / hearing about this example was in a probability class, however we didn&amp;rsquo;t actually write any code to try it, we just looked at the idea.</description></item><item><title>¿Qué Hace Mi Empresa?</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/qu%C3%A9-hace-mi-empresa/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 18:40:07 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/qu%C3%A9-hace-mi-empresa/</guid><description>Aviso: eso ha sido un trozo de texto que escribí para practicar mí español, no tiene nada que ver con FarSounder oficialmente.
Introducción En mi empresa, se llama FarSounder, hacemos un sistema de Sónar para los buques y los yates. El objetivo principal de este sistema es buscar cosas que sean peligrosas delante de la nave y bajo el agua. Hay un sensor que se pone en la proa, que está dirigido hacia delante, por supuesto.</description></item><item><title>Triplet Counting Algorithmic Puzzle</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/triplet-counting-algorithm-puzzle/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 21:05:24 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/triplet-counting-algorithm-puzzle/</guid><description>We’ve all got a little more time on our hands lately due to social distancing and COVID-19 (unless you have young children). I’ve been partly entertaining myself by learning new programming languages and frameworks, and also with some programming puzzles on sites like HackerRank.
I found one problem I ran into recently particularly interesting, and I enjoyed figuring it out (read: drove me crazy for a bit). This post is a write up of the problem and the solution that I ended up with.</description></item><item><title>Switching to the Python Pathlib Module</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/python-pathlib-module/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 20:32:39 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/python-pathlib-module/</guid><description>It’s been about a year or so since we officially upgraded all of our tooling at my job at FarSounder from Python 2.7 to Python 3 (3.6 at the moment). Aside from the syntactic changes, there have been a handful of updates in Python 3 that I’ve found to really increase the readability of our scripts. One of those updates (from back in Python 3.4) has been the introduction of the pathlib module.</description></item></channel></rss>