<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>project on Blogging by Heath™</title><link>https://heathhenley.github.io/tags/project/</link><description>Recent content in project on Blogging by Heath™</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 15:40:04 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://heathhenley.github.io/tags/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>YOLO-ing All the Traffic Cams</title><link>https://heathhenley.github.io/posts/yolo-all-the-traffic-cams/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 15:40:04 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.github.io/posts/yolo-all-the-traffic-cams/</guid><description>TL;DR - Here&amp;rsquo;s a web app to list labelled traffic cam images from the RI DOT website. I used YOLO (You Only Look Once) to detect objects (vehicles) in the images and FastAPI to serve the results to a React app. The app uses LeafletJS to display the images and the results. The backend is hosted on Railway and the front end on Github Pages. The code is available on GitHub.</description></item><item><title>New England Shipwreck Map</title><link>https://heathhenley.github.io/posts/simple-wreck-map/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 15:28:45 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.github.io/posts/simple-wreck-map/</guid><description>TL;DR - Here&amp;rsquo;s a list of shipwrecks plotted on an interactive map, all over the Narragansett Bay and greater New England area.
Motivation At FarSounder I work on the development software of 3D Forward Looking Sonar products. Part of that development process of course includes collecting data from a lot of different situations and running it through some processing algorithms to evaluate performance and make improvements. To that end, we&amp;rsquo;re often out on the Narragansett Bay collecting data with the system, and always looking for areas in the bay with interesting features that we can use to test and benchmark our algorithms (pilings, super steep shoals, rock piles, piers, etc).</description></item></channel></rss>