<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>software-engineering on Blogging by Heath™</title><link>https://heathhenley.github.io/categories/software-engineering/</link><description>Recent content in software-engineering on Blogging by Heath™</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 12:10:44 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://heathhenley.github.io/categories/software-engineering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Random Notes About Python's Random Module</title><link>https://heathhenley.github.io/posts/python-random-module-random-notes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 12:10:44 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.github.io/posts/python-random-module-random-notes/</guid><description>TL;DR: Use the functions in the random module for modeling, simulations, games, sampling, etc. but use os.urandom, secrets, or random.SystemRandom for cryptographic applications. I know very little about cryptography and security, these are just my notes about stuff I recently learned.
Random Notes About Python&amp;rsquo;s Random Module It uses the Mersenne Twister algorithm, which is a pseudorandom number generator with a period of 2^19937-1. It is one of the most widely used PRNGs in the world, and suitable for many applications.</description></item><item><title>Error Checking out Large Repo on GitHub Actions Windows Runner</title><link>https://heathhenley.github.io/posts/gh-actions-clone-windows-runner-error/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 18:07:36 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.github.io/posts/gh-actions-clone-windows-runner-error/</guid><description>TL;DR: If you&amp;rsquo;re getting a weird looking Error: fatal: fetch-pack: invalid index-pack output error checking out a large repo on a GitHub Actions using a Windows Runner, try switching to use HTTPS instead of SSH for your clones (by providing a personal access token instead of an SSH key).
Error Checking out Large Repo on GitHub Actions Windows Runner Summary I was recently working on getting CI setup for a project that has a pretty large repo with a few submodules and uses LFS for some large binaries.</description></item><item><title>Some tips for working at a small company (mostly for devs)</title><link>https://heathhenley.github.io/posts/small-company/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 19:01:27 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.github.io/posts/small-company/</guid><description>Some tips for Working at a Smaller Company (mostly for devs) TL;DR - A small company can be a great place to learn, and it can be a lot easier to see the effects of the results of your work. At the same time, you likely won’t have access to the same structure, level of mentorship, clarity of career path / progression, or resources. In my experience you need to be the kind of person who (1) is happy with being more of a generalist, and (2) take responsibility for your own learning - eg fill in gaps were necessary, go deeper when needed, and lean on outside resources, friends, etc.</description></item></channel></rss>