<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>thermodynamics on Blogging by Heath™</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/tags/thermodynamics/</link><description>Recent content in thermodynamics on Blogging by Heath™</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 09:19:59 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://heathhenley.dev/tags/thermodynamics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Modeling the Cooling in a Propane Tank</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/campstove-cheme/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 09:19:59 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/campstove-cheme/</guid><description>TL;DR: In a recent camping trip we noticed just how cold our propane tank was getting after cooking for a while - we started out pretty chilly anyway (about 50 F). The physics of this is cool and I wanted to play with modeling it.
I have one of these little two burner propane stoves that we use when camping, it looks something like this:
While we were cooking breakfast and boiling water for coffee, we noticed that the propane tank was getting super cold - there was not only a thick layer of frost forming on the outside, but a small chunk of solid ice on the bottom of the tank where it met the picnic table&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>ChE 513 Course Materials - ChE Thermodynamics (Graduate Level)</title><link>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/thermo-class-materials/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 13:08:44 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://heathhenley.dev/posts/thermo-class-materials/</guid><description>In the Fall of 2017, while finishing my PhD I taught ChE thermodynamics to a class of graduate and advanced undergraduate students at the University of Rhode Island. I recently discovered some of my old course materials and decided to post them publically. It was a project based class, so after the first few lectures, most of the class meetings were spent working on problems and projects.
Either way, I hope they are useful to someone!</description></item></channel></rss>